## YANN MARCOU

#### Senior Full-stack Developer



(514) 575-5443

yann17.marcou@gmail.com

https://creativeyann17.github.io

https://github.com/creativeyann17 🗹

#### **SKILLS**

#### Front-end

React.js | GraphQL | Redux | Saga | Jest Hooks | Bootstrap

## Back-end

Spring-boot | Micronaut | JUnit |
OpenAPI / Swagger

# Languages

Java | JavaScript | HTML / CSS / SCSS |
C# | C/C++

## **Tools**

Intelli] | VSCode | Git | Github | Atlassian | npm | yarn | maven | bash | Postman

#### **Databases**

MongoDB | H2 | PostgreSQL | Oracle |
Neo4j

# CI / CD / Cloud

Docker | Jenkins | Circle-ci | OpenShift |

Heroku | Google Cloud | GitHub Actions

## Embedded

Arduino | Raspberry-pi

#### Extra

Tech lead | Shopify | Gimp | Blender |

Agile methods







# **SOCIAL**

**\_** Twitter

@CreativeYann17 🗹

Linkedin

in yann-marcou-21280267 🗹

#### **ABOUT**

Hello, my name is Yann, French software developer. Until today I have worked on several personal / professional projects based on various kind of solutions: web, desktop and embedded. Different technologies were used like JAVA, JavaScript / HTML / CSS, C#, C/C++. I'm currently working abroad at Montreal.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Full-stack Developer at CGI / Facilité (Montréal) from October 2017 to February 2021

Context: CGI from May 2018 to February 2021

Description: <u>In continuity of Facilité (full-stack web developer)</u> + tech lead of the dev team, in charge of:

- code review + good practices (clean code)
- conception / analyze of new features
- production releases deployment / support

Context: Facilité from October 2017 to May 2018

**Description:** Full-stack web developer for an important Banking company using the best of today's web technologies.

**Technologies:** Java 8 / 11, Spring-boot, JUnit, Docker, OpenShift, Swagger, React.js, GraphQL, JS / TS / HTML / CSS

**Environment:** GitFlow, continuous integration, deployment and support of production env. MacOS, Visual Code, IntelliJ, Agile methods, npm, maven

# Analyst programmer at ATOS (Toulouse) from March 2011 to October 2017

Context: January 2016 to October 2017

Description: Full stack development of a web application (database, controller, model, view) which centralizes several sources of avionic maintenance reports in order to identify and provide support + prevention for airline companies fleets of aircraft by analyzing trends and relations between failures.

Technologies: Play Framework 1.2.7, H2, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, JAVA, JavaScript, SQL, XML, JSON, JQuery 1.x.x, vis.js, Angular 1.x, Bootstrap 3.x

Environment: Agile method (Scrum/Sprint), Cytoscape, Eclipse, Gimp,

Context: During 2015

Inkscape

**Description:** Development and testing of an XML periodic console application validator according to an XSD structure and internal checks. Once validated the model is inserted into database.

**Technologies:** C#, ZeroMQ, XML, XSD, Unit Tests, SQL Server, Visual Studio 2013, DotNET v4

Context: March 2011 to December 2014

Description: International Projects of R&D avionics maintenance.

Development and integration of real-time applications on CPM POSIX / A653.

Maintenance and prototyping of real-time applications in avionics simulation software and standalone tools used as script or model editor/validation.

Technologies: C/C++, STL, JAVA (J2SE, SWING, APPLET), Neo4J, GCC, GDB, XML, Visual Studio, POSIX, Cygwin, A653, Cytoscape

# **EDUCATION**

2007 - 2010 Master's degree in Engineering at ENSISA Mulhouse France

2005 - 2007 DUT (two-year technical degree in technology) Networks and Telecommunications at IUT (university institute of technology) Nancy-Brabois France

2002 - 2005 BAC scientific option engineering sciences at Lycée Marcel-Dassault France

## **HOBBY**

